Guide to the Isaac Levi Papers, 1949-2014 ASP.2016.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Research and Reviews, 1949-2014; III.
  - "Corroboration and Rules of Acceptance", 1963 (Box 35, Folder 3-4)
  - "Counterexamples to Recovery and the Filtering Condition", 1997 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - "Covenant of Reason Publishing Correspondence", 1996 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - "Decision and Revisions Cambridge University Press", 1984-1985 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - "Decision Theory and Confirmation", 1961 (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
  - "Deductive Closure", 2008 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - "Deductive Cogency in Inductive Inference", 1964-1965 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - "Demons of Decision", 1987 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - "Demons of Decision", undated (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - "Dewey Logic of Inquiry", undated (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - "Diachronic Rationality", 1997-1998 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - "Direct Inference and Confirmational Conditionalization", 1981 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - "Direct Inference and Randomization", 1982 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - "Direct Inference", 1975-1977 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - "Dispositions and Conditionals", 2000-2002 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - "Dissonance and Consistency According to Shackle and Shafer", 1978-1981 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - "Doubt, Context and Inquiry", 1982 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - "Doxastic States", c. 2008 (Box 35, Folder 22-23)
  - Educational Testing Service (ETS), 1982 (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Ellsburg, Daniel Introduction and Research Correspondence, 1989-2000 (Box 35, Folder 25-26)
  - Encyclopedia of Philosophy, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Enterprise of Knowledge Publishing Correspondence and Information, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Enterprise of Knowledge Reviews, 1980-1984 (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - "Epicycles", 1985 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - "Epistemic Logic", undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - "Epistemic Risk", 2014 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - "Epistemic Utility and the Evaluation of Experiments", 1976 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - "Estimation and Error Free Information", 1985-1986 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - "Ethics of Controversy" (Rutgers), March 3, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - "Evidentiary Mechanisms and Routine Expansion", 1993-1995 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - "Evolution and Reduction", 1959 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - "Feasibility", 1989-1991 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - "Fixation of Belief and it's Undoing" (Cambridge University Press), 1990-1992 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - "Fixation of Belief and it's Undoing" Reviews, 1991-1994 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - "For the Sake of Argument" Publishing Correspondence (Cambridge University Press), 1994 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Fuhrmann, Andre and Isaac Levi, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Gambling with Truth Reviews, c. 1960s (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Gardenfors, Peter Reviews, 1988-1991 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - "Hacking Salmon on Induction", 1965 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Hallden Festschrift, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - "Hard Choices: Decisions Under Unresolved Conflict" Reviews, 1986-1992 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Harper's Encyclopedia of Science Entries, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Harrod, Ray, "Foundations of Inductive Logic" Review, 1956-1958 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Harvard Educational Review Review of Anatol Rapoport, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - "Hedging Acceptance", 1992 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Hertwig, Ralph "Conjunction Fallacy" Review, 1998-2006 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Hill, Bruce, Comment by Levi, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - History of Science, 1949-1959 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - "How Infallible but Corrigible Belief is Possible", undated (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - "How to Fix a Prior", 1993 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - "Identity and Conflict" (for Social Research), 2006-2009 (Box 36, Folder 28-29)
  - "If Jones Only Knew More!", 1968 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - "Ignorance, Probability and Rational Choice", 1982 (Box 36, Folder 31-32)
  - "Irrelevance", 1975-1978 (Box 36, Folder 33)
  - "Imprecise and Indeterminate Probabilities", 2000 (Box 36, Folder 34)
  - "Imprecision and Indeterminacy in Probability Judgement", 1985 (Box 36, Folder 35)
  - "Incognizables", 1980 (Box 36, Folder 36)
  - "Independence of Irrelevant Alternatives: A Re-Examination", undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - "Indeterminate Probabilities", 1974 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - "Induction According to Pierce", 1989 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - "Induction as Self Correcting According to Peirce", 1979 (Box 37, Folder 4-5)
  - "Inductive Expansion According to Caution Dependent, Deductively Cogent and Partition Sensitive Criteria" Drafts, 1997-1998 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - "Information and Error", 1982 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - "Information and Ignorance", 1982 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - "Information and Inference", 1966-1969 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - "Is a Miss as Good as a Mile?", undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - "Iteration of Conditionals and the Ramsey Test", 1985-1988 (Box 37, Folder 11-12)
  - Jaakko Hintikka Essay, 2001-2004 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - "Jeffrey Conditionalization", 1983 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Kahneman, Slovic and Tversky "Judgement Under Uncertainty: Heuristics and Biases" Review, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - "Keynes on the Weight of Argument", undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Kitcher, Phillip Research Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - "Knowledge and True Belief", undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Kyburg: Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 19-20)
  - Kyburg on Random Designations, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Kyburg, Henry E., "The Dutch Book Argument and Rational Belief", 2000 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - "Kyburg's Frequency Principle", undated (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Lawrence Skylar "Unfair to Frequencies", 1971 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Lehrer, Keith, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - "Liberty and Value", 1981 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - "Liberty and Value", 1981 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - "Liberty and Welfare", undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - "Madden Structure of Scientific Thought", 1961 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - "Maximizing and Satisficing Evidential Support", no date (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Mellor, D.H., "The Facts of Causation", 1995 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - "Messianic vs Myopic Realism" (PSA Paper), 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Mil"d Contraction: Evaluating Loss Information Due to Loss of Belief" Review, 2005 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Misak, Cheryl (Pragmatism), 1997 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - MIT Press, 1972-1982 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - "Must the Scientist Make Value Judgements?", c. 1960s (Box 38, Folder 10-11)
  - "Naturalism", 2007 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - New York Review of Books, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - "Newcombe's Many Problems", 1975 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - "Newcombmania", 1992 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Nils-Eric Sahlin Philosophy of F.P. Ramsey, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - O'Flaherty, Brendan and Jagdish Bhagwati, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - "Objective Modality and Direct Inference", 1999-2000 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - "Objective Modality and Direct Inference", 2001 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - "Objective Modality and Direct Inference", 2001-2003 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - "On Potential Surprise", 1965-1968 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - "On Potential Surprise", undated (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - "On the Seriousness of Mistakes", 1961-1962 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Paper on Rudolph Carnap, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Paper on Tversky and Kahneman, 1980-1983 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - "Paradoxes of Alias and Ellesberg", 1981-1986 (Box 38, Folder 26-28)
  - "Pareto Unanimity and Consensus", 1988-1990 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - "Pareto Unanimity and Consensus", 1990 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Pierce in Toronto, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Pierce, 1994-1995 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Pietarinen, Ahti-Veikko, 2014 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Popper, Karl and David Miller, 1984-1986 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - "Possibility and Probability", 1989 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - "Potential Surprise, It's Role in Inference", 1977-1978 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - "Pragmastism and the Value of Truth", 1994 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - "Probabilistic Pettifoggery", 1985 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - "Probability and Evidence", undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - "Probability Independent Preference" (Reply to Leeds), 1990 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - "Probability Independent Utility" (Review of Leeds), 1990 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - "Probability Kinematics", 1967 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - "Probability Kinematics", undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - "Probability Logic and Logical Probability", undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - "Probability Logic, Logical Probability and Inductive Support", 2008 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - "Probability, Value and Belief", 1998-1999 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - "Prospective Theory and Cognitive Fallacies", 1997 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Publishing Correspondence and Information, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Publishing Correspondence and Information, 1982-1989 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - "Putnam's Three Truth Values", 1959 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Random House, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - "Randomization", c. 1950s-1980s (Box 39, Folder 23-24)
  - "Rationality and Commitment", 1994 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - "Rationality Unbound", 1990 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - "Rationality, Prediction and Autonomous Choice", 1991 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Reply to Caldwell and Lehrer, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Reply to Keith Lehrer, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Reply to Maher, 1988-1989 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Reply to Maher and Kashima, 1990-1991 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - "Representing Preferences: Donald Davidson on Rational Choice", 1996-1997 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Research Correspondence, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Review for Hintikka, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Review of Arthur Burks "Chance, Cause, Reason", 1981 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Review of "Aspects of Inductive Logic", 1966 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Review of Clark Glymour "Theory and Evidence", 1980 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Review of "Concepts, Theories and the Mind-Body Problem" (Minnesota Studies), 1961 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Review of "Concepts, Theories and the Mind-Body Problem" (Minnesota Studies II), 1961 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Review of Frederic Schick "Making Choices: A Recasting of Decision Theory", 1997 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Review of Gilbert Harman "Change in View", 1986 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Review of Henry E. Kyburg "Epistemology and Inference", 1983-1986 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Review of Hugh Mellor's "Matter of Chance", 1972 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Review of Hughes Leblanc, "Statistics and Inductive Probabilities", 1961-1963 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Review of Irme Lakatos "The Problem of Inductive Logic", 1968 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Review of Patrick Suppes "Probabilistic Metaphysics", 1988 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Review of R.C. Jeffrey "Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability", 1982 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Review of R.C. Jeffrey "Studies in Inductive Logic and Probability", 1983 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Review of Soren Hallden "The Strategy of Ignorance", 1988 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Review of Watkins "Science and Skepticism", 1985 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Review of Wesley J. Salmon "The Foundations of Scientific Inference", 1966 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Rorty, Richard, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Routledge Encyclopedia of Philosophy Entry on Nagel, 1993-1994 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Routledge Encyclopedia of Philosophy- Nagel, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - "Seeking Truth" (Second Revision), 2000 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - "Seeking Truth", 2000 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - "Seeking Truth", 2002 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Sen, Amartya reviews by Levy, 2002-2004 (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Sheffler, I., American Philosophical Association, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - "Subjunctives, Dispositions and Chances", 1977 (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - Suppes, Hintikka J. Review by Levi, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - "Support and Surprise: L.J. Cohen's View of Inductive Probability", 1979 (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - "Supposing Isn't Believing: A Response to Chalmers and Hajek", 2007 (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - "Supposition and Belief Change", 2004 (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - "The Logic of Full Belief", 1994-1996 (Box 40, Folder 36)
  - "The Second Worst in Practical Conflict", 2000-2003 (Box 40, Folder 37)
  - "The Wrong Box", 1983 (Box 40, Folder 38)
  - Theoria Journal, 2006 (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - "Truth, Fallibility and the Growth of Knowledge", 1975-1981 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - "Truth, Fallibility and the Growth of Knowledge", 1983 (Box 41, Folder 2-3)
  - "Undercutting and the Ramsey Test for Conditionals" (Levi and Andre Fuhrmann), 1992 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - "Value Commitments, Value Conflict and Separability of Belief and Value", 1999 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Voice of America Philosophy of Science Series, 1962-1964 (Box 41, Folder 6-7)
  - Walliser, Zwirn and Zwirn, "Abductive Logics in a Belief Revision Framework", 2005 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - "Weslyan Conference on Induction", June 1961 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - "Zealous Acceptance", 1978 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Zwrin and Zwirn, "Metaconfirmation" Paper, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 11)
- Photographs, IV.
  Series IV. Photographs contains digital photographs documenting Levi's personal and professional life including colleagues, family members and professional conferences. Please contact Archives & Special Collections to arrange access.
  - Photographs from Hugh Mellor, 1978-2007; 1.
    - 1978-073 Oxford Inductive Logic Conference members, ?, ?, Paul Teller, ?, Isaac Levi, Radu Bogdan, August 23, 1978 (Box 41, Item 1)
    - 1980-002 Richard Braithwaite's 80th birthday party Richard's Living Room, 11 Millington Road Margaret Masterman, Dorothy Emmet, Fred Schick, Stephan Körner, Isaac Levi, ?, Judy Levi, Mary Hesse, Hugh Mellor, Nick Jardine, January 17, 1980 (Box 41, Item 2)
    - 1993-025 Cambridge Moral Sciences Club Philosophers shown include David Lewis, Alex Oliver, Derek Matravers, Peter Smith, Rosanna Keefe, Edward Craig, Joseph Melia, Huw Price, Timothy Smiley, Isaac Levi, Hugh Mellor, Henry Krips, Dorothy Emmet, John Waugh, Melissa Lane, Jane Heal, Jonathan Harrison, Fiona Campbell, John Bradley, May 4, 1983 (Box 41, Item 3)
    - 1997-004 London Covent Garden Hugh Mellor, March 22, 1997 (Box 41, Item 4)
    - 2005-0039 New York, Philip & Patricia Kitcher's apartment, Apt 5b 454 Riverside Drive Steffi Lewis, Isaac Levi, April 9, 2005 (Box 41, Item 5)
    - 2007-100 Lund Nils-Eric Sahlin, Isaac Levi (Picture © Johannes Persson), May 8, 2007 (Box 41, Item 6)
  - Photographs of Isaac Levi, 1932-2000; 2.
    - Img001 w/ Fred Schick in Springs, NY, c. 1995 (Box 41, Item 1)
    - Img002 w/ Helen Weinberg, Sam Levin, Flora Levin, Carol & Albert Cook, c. mid 1990s (Box 41, Item 2)
    - Img005 w/ Brother in law Abby Rubins, Wilfried Sieg, c. 1995 (Box 41, Item 3)
    - Img006 w/ Albert Cook, Cleveland, c. 1965 (Box 41, Item 4)
    - Img007 w/ Jack McLellan & Mortimer Kadish, c. 1962 (Box 41, Item 5)
    - Img008 w/ Sam Levin, Jack McLellan, Albert & Jonathan Cook, c. 1962 (Box 41, Item 6)
    - Img009 w/ Martin Klein, Sam Levin, Judith Levi, Raymond Nelson, undated (Box 41, Item 7)
    - Img010 w/ Nina McLellan, Hendrika Nelson, Mortimer Kadish, c. 1962 (Box 41, Item 8)
    - Img011 w/ Nina McLellan, Judith Levi, Jack McLellan, Ruth and Mortimer Kadish, c. 1960 (Box 41, Item 9)
    - Img0012 w/ Abe Kaplan, Fred Schick, and Eugene Gadol, c. 1963 (Box 41, Item 10)
    - Img0014 w/ Teddy Seidenfeld in Cinqueterre, Italy, c. 1991 (Box 41, Item 11)
    - Img016 @ All Soul's College, 1988 (Box 41, Item 12)
    - Img017 @ All Soul's College, 1988 (Box 41, Item 13)
    - Img018 w/ Arnold Koslow, c. 1988 (Box 41, Item 14)
    - Img019 w/ Peter Gärdenfors, undated (Box 41, Item 15)
    - Img020 in Lund, Sweden on occasion of Honorary Degree, 1988 (Box 41, Item 16)
    - Img021 w/ Thomas Campbell (historian and politician) and Ruth Kadish, undated (Box 41, Item 17)
    - Img027 w/ Nils-Erik Sahlin & Peter Gärdenfors @ Lund, 1988 (Box 41, Item 18)
    - Img029 w/ Edith & Ernest Nagel @ Vershire, Vermont, c. 1980 (Box 41, Item 19)
    - Img033 w/ Hugh Mellor @ Covent Garden, c. 1988 (Box 41, Item 20)
    - Img034 w/ Henry Kyburg recipient Butler Medal, 1982 (Box 41, Item 21)
    - Img035 w/ Dorothy Emmet, c. 1997 (Box 41, Item 22)
    - Img045 w/ Raymond Nelson, Cleveland, c. 1958 (Box 41, Item 23)
    - Img057 upstate NY, c. 1947 (Box 41, Item 24)
    - Img058 Bar-Mitzvah, Branford, Ontario, 1943 (Box 41, Item 25)
    - Img059 NYC, 1952 (Box 41, Item 26)
    - Img060 Branford Collegiate Institute & Vocational School, Branford, Ontario (studied there during WWII), undated (Box 41, Item 27)
    - Img061 NYC, c. 1975 (Box 41, Item 28)
    - Img071 Detroit, 1947 (Box 41, Item 29)
    - Img075 Brooklyn, NY, 1955 (Box 41, Item 30)
    - Img076 Vershire, VT, 1970 (Box 41, Item 31)
    - Img083 w/ brother David B. Levi, c. 1940 (Box 41, Item 32)
    - Img124 w/ Anthropologist Robert I. Levy, Wengen, Switzerland, 1991 (Box 41, Item 33)
    - Img130 Officiating at wedding of niece Dr. Deborah Schrag and Yochai Benkler, undated (Box 41, Item 34)
    - Img145 w/ sons Jonathan and David, Martha's Vineyard, 1978 (Box 41, Item 35)
    - Img146 w/ Henry & Sarah Kyburg, Teddy & Janice Seidenfeld & Judith Levi @ Lake Constanz, c. 2000 (Box 41, Item 36)
    - Img156 w/ mother Eva Lunenfeld Levi, c. 1932 (Box 41, Item 37)
    - Img157 w/ father Rabbi Eliezer Asher Levi c. probably in Birmingham, AL, c. 1932 (Box 41, Item 38)
    - Img209 @ office in Columbia University, c. 1985 (Box 41, Item 39)